These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2025-08 were created by ZoowlCZ.
ⓘ Very special thanks to Gwaith-i-Phethdain, Magpie of A Magpie's Nest and Friends, and Monoverantus
for their extraordinary work on deciphering the dialogs and lyrics.
ⓘ Special thanks also to TheGloriousLori and José Figueredo.
ⓘ For correct displaying of these subtitles, use a media player
supporting ASS tags in .srt files.
[Sindarin] ♫ Man ammen toltha i dann hen morn? ♫
[English] ♫ Who brings to us this token of darkness? ♫
[Sindarin] I amar prestar aen.
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne nen.
[Sindarin] ♫ Si dannatha, nauva. ♫
[English] ♫ Will now fall, will be. ♫
[Sindarin] Han mathon ne chae.
[Sindarin] A han noston ned 'wilith.
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nênâkham nêpâm... ♫
[English] ♫ We approach, we grasp... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...abâr-at... ♫
[English] ♫ ...power and... ♫
[Sindarin] Tangado haid!
[English] Hold positions!
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...aglar. ♫
[English] ♫ ...glory. ♫
[Sindarin] Leithio i philinn!
[English] Release the arrows!
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêtabdam dâurad. ♫
[English] ♫ We cling to the darkness. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nidir nêpâm. ♫
[English] ♫ The Nine, we grasp. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêpâm nêd... ♫
[English] ♫ We grasp for ourselves... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...aglar. ♫
[English] ♫ ...glory. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nênâkham nêpâm... ♫
[English] ♫ We approach, we grasp... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...abâr-at... ♫
[English] ♫ ...power and... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...aglar. ♫
[English] ♫ ...glory. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêbâbîtham Magânanê. ♫
[English] ♫ We renounce our Creator. ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ Rîn athar annún-aearath ... ♫
[English] ♫ O Queen beyond the Western Seas... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ... calad ammen ... ♫
[English] ♫ ... light to us ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ... i reniar ... ♫
[English] ♫ ... who wander ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ... mi 'aladhremmin Ennorath. ♫
[English] ♫ ... amid the tree-woven lands of Middle-earth. ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ A Elbereth Gilthoniel ... ♫
[English] ♫ O Elbereth Star-kindler ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫ ... i chin a thûl lín míriel. ♫
[English] ♫ ... your eyes and breath shining like jewels. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Bârî'n Katha-râd... ♫
[English] ♫ The Lords of the Eternal life... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...îdô Nidir... ♫
[English] ♫ ...now the Nine... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...nênâ-kham, nêpâm... ♫
[English] ♫ ...we come, we grasp... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...abarat aglar. ♫
[English] ♫ ...power and glory. ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  Tinúviel elvanui ...  ♫
[English] ♫ Tinúviel elven-fair ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  ... elleth alfirin edhelhael ...  ♫
[English] ♫ ... immortal maiden elven-wise ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  ... o hon ring finnil fuinui ...  ♫
[English] ♫ ... about him cast her night-dark hair ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  ... a renc gelebrin.  ♫
[English] ♫ ... and arms like silver. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Bârî'n Katha-râd ♫
[English] ♫ The Lords of the Eternal life ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Îdô Nidir Nê ♫
[English] ♫ Now we Nine ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêbâ-bîtham ♫
[English] ♫ We deny ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Dir Nê Nâkham ♫
[English] ♫ We Nine approach ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêbâ-bîtham Ma-gâna-nanê ♫
[English] ♫ We renounce our Creator ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ Nêtab~ Dâur~ ♫
[English] ♫ We cling to the darkness ♫
[Black Speech] Gûm-ishi...
[English] In the void...
[Black Speech] ...ashi...
[English] ...only...
[Black Speech] ...gurum!
[English] ...death!
[Quenya] ♫  I Cemen Nurrua ...  ♫
[English] ♫ The earth groans ... ♫
[Quenya] ♫  ... ar i súre...  ♫
[English] ♫ ... and the wind ... ♫
[Quenya] ♫  ... i sú-re ...  ♫
[English] ♫ ... the wind ... ♫
[Quenya] ♫  ... naina.  ♫
[English] ♫ ... is crying. ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  Tinuviel elvanui ...  ♫
[English] ♫ Tinuviel the elven-fair ... ♫
[Sindarin] ♫  ... elleth alfirin.  ♫
[English] ♫ ... immortal maiden. ♫
[Sindarin] Im Arwen, Telin le thaed.
[English] I Arwen, I come to help you.
[Sindarin] Lasto beth nîn, tolo dan nan galad.
[English] Listen to my word, come back to the light.
[Sindarin] Dartho guin Beriain. Rych le ad tolthathon.
[English] Stay with the Hobbits. I will send horses for you.
[Sindarin] Hon mabathon! Rochon ellint im.
[English] I will take him! I am the swifter rider.
[Sindarin] Andelu i ven.
[English] The road is too dangerous.
[Sindarin] Frodo fîr. Ae athradon i hîr ...
[English] Frodo is dying. If I cross the river ...
[Sindarin] ... tûr gwaith nîn beriatha hon.
[English] ... the power of my people will protect him.
[Sindarin] Be iest lîn.
[English] As you wish.
[Sindarin] Noro lim Asfaloth, noro lim!
[English] Ride fast Asfaloth, ride fast!
[Adûnaic] ♫  Bârî 'n Katharâd...  ♫
[English] ♫ Lords of the eternal life... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫  ...îdô kham nêpâm.  ♫
[English] ♫ ...now approaching we grasp. ♫
[Sindarin] Noro lim Asfaloth!
[English] Ride fast Asfaloth!
[Adûnaic] ♫  Nênâkham, nêpâm...  ♫
[English] ♫ We approach, we grasp... ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫ ...abarat aglar. ♫
[English] ♫ ...power and glory. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫  Nêpâm nêd aglar.  ♫
[English] ♫ We grasp for ourselves glory. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫  Nidir, nêpâm.  ♫
[English] ♫ The Nine, we grasp. ♫
[Adûnaic] ♫  Nêpâm nêd aglar.  ♫
[English] ♫ We grasp for ourselves glory. ♫
[Sindarin] Nîn o Chithaeglir, lasto beth daer!
[English] Waters of the Misty Mountains, listen to the great word!
[Sindarin] Rimmo nîn Bruinen dan in Ulaer!
[English] Flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths!
[Sindarin] Nîn o Chithaeglir, lasto beth daer!
[English] Waters of the Misty Mountains, listen to the great word!
[Sindarin] Rimmo nîn Bruinen dan in Ulaer!
[English] Flow waters of Loudwater against the Ringwraiths!
[Sindarin] Lasto beth nîn. Tolo dan nan galad.
[English] Hear my voice. Come back to the light.
[Sindarin] A si i-Dhúath ú-orthor, Aragorn.
[English] The shadow does not hold sway yet, Aragorn.
[Sindarin] Ú or le a ú or nin.
[English] Not over you, not over me.
[Sindarin] Renich i lú i erui govannem?
[English] Do you remember when we first met?
[Sindarin] Nauthannen i ned ôl reniannen.
[English] I thought I had strayed into a dream.
[Sindarin] Gwenwin in enninath.
[English] Long years have passed.
[Sindarin] Ú-'arnech in naeth i si celich.
[English] You did not wear the troubles you carry now.
[Sindarin] Renich i beth i pennen?
[English] Do you remember what I told you?
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Sherkuk-ishi
[English] In your blood
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Shre nazg golugranu kilmi-nudu...
[English] Three Rings for the Elven-kings under the sky...
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul...
[English] ...One ring to find them...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Ombi kuzd-durbagu... shirku
[English] Seven for the Dwarf-lords... blood
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg thrakatulûk...
[English] ...One ring to bring them all...
(The Ring)
[Black Speech] Ash Burz-Durbagu burzum-ishi...
[English] One for the Dark lord on his dark throne...
(Gandalf)
[Black Speech] ...Agh burzum-ishi krimpatul.
[English] ...and in the darkness bind them.
[Sindarin] Havo dad, Legolas.
[English] Sit down, Legolas.
[Black Speech] Daghburz-ishi makha, ghurarmu shirku.
[English] In the land of Mordor, a sacrifice of blood.
[Black Speech] Makha gulshu darulu.
[English] Where the Shadows lie.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...
[Black Speech] ...Ash nazg gimbatul.
[English] ...One ring to find them.
[Black Speech] Ash nazg durbatulûk...
[English] One ring to rule them all...